Guide to the Don Stitt Collected Plays MS 049
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Don Stitt Collected Plays
1974-2007
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Stitt, Don
MS 049
145
1 Linear Feet, 2 boxes
Don Stitt is an actor, writer, director, choreographer and composer who began his career in the mid 1960s. He received his MFA from WCSU in 2007. The collection includes his written work created throughout his career in the theater.
Historical Biographical Note
Don Stitt is an actor, writer, director, choreographer and composer who began his career in the mid 1960s. He was born in 1956, in Stamford, CT. He attended San Francisco State University and while there wrote the book, music and lyrics for Babes on 42nd Street, The Doonesbury Revue, Joy, and A Kid's Summer Night's Dream. He was a professional actor through the 1970s based in California and continued to write for the theater. In 1976, he was in the cast of Beach Blanket Babylon. The following year he was featured in the first Equity production of The Great American Backstage Musical, performing it in San Francisco and Palm Springs.
In 1978, Stitt created a revue called Irving Berlin in Revue, which ran for two years (and enjoyed a revival in 1993.) He then relocated to New York City where he directed an Equity production of his children's piece, A Kid's Summer Night's Dream in 1979. Later that year, he choreographed Godspell and appeared in Man of La Mancha and Grease for the Burt Reynolds Dinner Theater.
In the 1980s, he made his Broadway debut in Do Black Patent Leather Shoes Really Reflect Up?, and returned in Late Nite Comic a few seasons later. (The latter is the subject of the book We Bombed in New London.) Stitt was integral to the New York revival of El Grande de Coca Col a at The Village Gate and toured with Chita Rivera and the Radio City Music Hall Rockettes for over a year in Can-Can.
In the 1990s, he played in Alan Freed in Buddy: The Buddy Holly Story and played Marcus Lycus in the revival of A Funny Thing Happened on the Way to the Forum on Broadway and was prominent as a commercial actor in hundreds of spots as an on-camera and/or voice-over actor.
Stitt also made some brief appearances in some feature films, including Fame, Simon, Stardust Memories, The Wanderers, and World Trade Center.
More recently, Stitt has played the Mayor of Whoville, first in the National Tour of the Broadway musical Seussical, (which starred Olympic gymnast Cathy Rigby as the Cat in the Hat,) and another production at the Fulton Opera House in Lancaster, PA. He has also appeared on television's "Law & Order," and made his 15th appearance on "The Late Show with David Letterman" in 2005. That same year, he also played Elton John in the world premiere of A Girl Called Dusty at the Provincetown Playhouse.
He received an MFA in playwriting from Western Connecticut State University in 2007, where premiered a one-man show called The Voices in My Head Have Formed a Choir and Somebody's Singing Flat!, as well as a comedy called Civil Intercourse.
He is married to Professor Elizabeth Popiel of WCSU, who is also a resident scenic designer for Good Morning America.
Stitt currently lives in New York City.
Sources:
Evans, Seth (undated). Don Stitt Professional Actor/Comedian. Retrieved April 14, 2009, from http://sethevans.net/ Web site: http://sethevans.net/roscoe/bios/donbio.htm
Scope and Content Note
This is a collection of Don Stitt's works ranging from the 1974-2008. Stitt's Master's thesis is also housed in Special Collections but is not yet cataloged.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged into one series.
Provenance
Donated by Don Stitt in 2009.
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers without restriction.
Related Material
Don Stitt's Master's Thesis (not yet cataloged).
Scripts (documents).; Videotapes.; Drafts (documents).; Stitt, Don
- Inventory, 41726
  - The collected plays of Don Stitt - play summaries w/ photo, 2008; 41741 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Summary of Don Stitt Plays from 1974 to 2004 and b&w photograph
  - Babes On 42nd Street, 1974; 41740 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Script of Don Stitt Play
  - The Doonesbury Review, 1975; 41739 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Script of play
  - Irving Berlin "In Review", 1978; 41738 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Joy, 1976; 41737 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A Kid's Summer Night's Dream 1/3, 1978; 41736 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Early Drafts of Score to play
  - A Kid's Summer Night's Dream 2/3, 1978; 41735 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - A Kid's Summer Night's Dream 3/3, 1978; 41734 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Vocal/Piano/Guitar Lead sheets from Score of Don Stitt play with CD
  - Potshots, 1979; 41733 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Rosco 1/2, 2000; 41732 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Roscoe 2/2, 2000; 41731 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Lead Score and CD of play
  - Wits' End or Last Night at the Round Table, 1984; 41730 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Vicious Circle or Nights at the Round Table, 2004; 41729 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    First draft Script
  - The Voices In My Head Have Formed A Choir And Somebody's Singing Flat, 2004-2007; 41728 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Script of play, with 2 DVDs of a 2007 staging of the work.
  - Dick Cheney: The Musical, 2011; 56412 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Irving Berlin "In Review" .... [video], 1978; 41727 (Box 2, Item 1)
    U-matic video (ucs 20)
  - "Too Marvelous", 2013; 57750 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    General
    2 DVD-Rs - 1 recorded in Lancaster, PA, 1 from "Don't Tell Momma" in NYC 7/7/13.
  - A Kid's Summer Night's Dream Audio Recording, 1978 (Box 2, Item 2)
  - Potshots, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    CD of the New York showcase of Potshots at the Network Theatre in 51st and 9th.
  - Crayons, 1972 (Box 2, Item 3)
    An animated film of the secret life of crayons on 8mm film.
  - Maybe This'll Help, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 3)